Guide to the Jacob Harvey Family Papers 1811-1994 MS 306
New-York Historical Society
- Series III. Feins Research Notes, 1811-1994; 3 Linear feet
  - Subseries III.B. Hosack Research Notes, 1811-1982; 2.75 Linear feet
    - Research Notes. American Medical & Philosophical Register, circa 1950 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 25)
    - Research Notes. Medical Journals, circa 1950 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 26)
    - Research Notes. Libraries, circa 1950 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 27)
    - Research Notes. American Philosophical Society, circa 1950 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 28)
    - Research Notes. College of Physicians & Surgeons, circa 1950 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 29)
    - Research Notes. Columbia College, circa 1950 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 1)
    - Research Notes. Museum of the City of New York Bibliography - New York Literature, circa 1950 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 2)
    - Research Notes. New-York Historical Society, circa 1950 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 3)
    - Research Notes. Rutgers Medical College, circa 1950 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 4)
    - Research Notes. Francis Papers, circa 1950 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 5)
    - Research Notes. Pintard Letters, circa 1950 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 6)
    - Research Notes. Bard, Burr, Chervin, Clinton, circa 1950 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 7)
    - Research Notes. Dunlap, Hamilton, Hamilton-Burr Duel, Jefferson, circa 1950 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 8)
    - Research Notes. Morris, Stevens, Rush, Verplank, circa 1950 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 9)
    - Research Notes. Wharton, circa 1950 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 10)
    - Research Notes. New York City Hospital, circa 1950 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 11)
    - Research Notes. NYC - Health of, Almshouse, Bellevue Hospital, circa 1950 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 12)
    - Research Notes. NYC - Practice of Physicians, circa 1950 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 13)
    - Research Notes. NYC - American Academy of Fine Art, circa 1950 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 14)
    - Research Notes. NYC - Art, Directories, Dispensary, circa 1950 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 15)
    - Research Notes. NYC - Education, History, Horticultural Societies, circa 1950 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 16)
    - Research Notes. NYC - Humane Society, Literature Magazines, circa 1950 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 17)
    - Research Notes. NYC - Newspapers, circa 1950 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 18)
    - Research Notes. NYC - Lying In Hospital, New York Society Library, Sport, circa 1950 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 19)
    - Research Notes. NYC - Theater, Medical Society, Agricultural Society, circa 1950 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 20)
    - Research Notes. NY State - Medical Society, Politics, Prison, circa 1950 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 21)
    - Research Notes. To File, circa 1950 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 22)
    - Research Notes. Miscellaneous (8 Folders), circa 1950 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 23-30)
      These folders consist predominantly of notecards and typescripts prepared by the Feinses. There is also a small amount correspondence between the Feinses and various people and institutions regarding the location and nature of research resources pertaining to the life and work of David Hosack. Of particular interest are correspondence with the Biddle sisters and Christine C. Robbins.
      Folder 23: includes, among other documents, correspondence between the director of the Museum of the City of New York and Constance Biddle (1947) which was forwarded by Biddle to Claire Feins, on the topic of Hosack manuscripts and the Coster family.
      Folder 24: includes, among other documents, correspondence between Constance Biddle, John Hampton Barnes, and Claire Feins regarding some Hosack material, including a portrait that may, or may not, have been painted by John Trumbull, and some sketchbooks that may have been lost in the mail.
      Folder 25: includes, among other documents, correspondence between Christine C. Robbins and Claire Feins.
    - Research Notes. Manuscript for an Article Titled "The Romance of New York City Land", circa 1950 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 31)
      Includes an article written by Daniel Feins, and sent for consideration to the New York Times Magazine, in 1941. Also included are several drafts of the article, a letter from Feins to the editor, and a letter of rejection from the magazine.
    - Research Notes. W.P.A. Objective Teaching Materials, circa 1950 (Offsite-box 14, Folder --)
      An empty binder from which some of the typescripts prepared by the Feinses were pulled.